<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>J. Alejandro Nanga</title>
    <description>Mexican 3D artist and video game developer</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 16:14:01 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 16:14:01 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.0</generator>

    
      <item>
        <title>About me</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a 3D artist from Mexico. I’m currently developing in Unity for WebGL and VR/AR platforms, focusing on level design, environmental art and polygon optimization for platforms with hardware limitations, at Thermo Fisher Scientific.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My workflow consists on scouting, conceptualizing, modeling with Autodesk Maya, texturing with Substance Painter and Adobe Photoshop for PBR shaders and then moving to Unity3D to populate environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I care about improving processes to deliver faster, consistent, high quality work in 3D environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/VQlVqDa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Personal avatar&quot; width=&quot;33%&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:me@nanga.mx&quot;&gt;Contact me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/01/about-me/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/01/01/about-me/</guid>
      </item>
    

    
      
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>CV</title>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;experience&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Experience&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;thermo-fisher-scientific-2017---present&quot;&gt;Thermo Fisher Scientific (2017 - Present)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;3d-technical-artist-2020---present&quot;&gt;3D Technical Artist (2020 - Present)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My role inside of Thermo Fisher Scientific is working with Pharma Services Global to create 3D replicas of their pharmaceutical laboratories at a very low hardware cost parting from photographic scans; for AR applications for the HoloLens 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;software-engineer-i--3d-developer-2017---2020&quot;&gt;Software Engineer I / 3D Developer (2017 - 2020)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2017 to 2020, I was an interdisciplinary team member in the Digital Engineering division. Among my responsibilities was the development of 3D assets for applications on WebGL and VR/AR platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in charge of doing the retopology of Thermo Fisher’s biotechnology equipment parting from provided CAD files to textured low polycount meshes, for a WebGL training application for new users of these instruments. In this experience I was also responsible for creating the animations of each workflow, ranging from the installation of the instrument to running experiments with them; I also recreated the Software User Interface for Unity’s UI elements and every 3D asset required for these workflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked on a POC on the interconnection of an experience made in Unity for the HTC Vive and a real life lab automation Spinnaker Microplate Robot, where I modeled the instruments required and the virtual environment itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore I functioned as an environmental artist creating asset bundles of cellular, molecular and protein biology for a training video game for the Oculus Go. Where I scouted different laboratories of Thermo Fisher Scientific, made the layouts and concept art and continued modeling, optimizing, creating texture atlas for each asset bundle with few draw calls and a low polycount as the main priorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also worked on creating different User Interfaces for our projects and implementing others with templates from the User Interface and User Experience department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of my goals for the company I provided courses on the creation of 3D assets for video games for interested coworkers on vastly different areas of Digital Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vicom-2017&quot;&gt;Vicom (2017)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;intern-in-media&quot;&gt;Intern in Media&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Vicom I worked as an intern in media. My responsibilities were filling the gap between disciplines in the media department. Fulfilling the needs of different clients based mostly at the central Mexico region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in charge of creating 2D assets for motion graphics; 2D animation; assisting at brand storytelling; graphic design for web; and product photography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;education&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Education&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;monterrey-institute-of-technology-and-higher-education-2012---2017&quot;&gt;Monterrey Institute of Technology and Higher Education (2012 - 2017)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;ba-animation-and-digital-art&quot;&gt;B.A. Animation and digital art&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;universidad-católica-de-murcia--coco-school-2015---2016&quot;&gt;Universidad Católica de Murcia / Coco School (2015 - 2016)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;m-3d-modeling-animation-and-visual-effects&quot;&gt;M. 3D modeling, animation and visual effects&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;skills&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Skills&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;media&quot;&gt;Media:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Autodesk Maya&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adobe CC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Substance Painter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;V-Ray&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arnold&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pixologic ZBrush&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blender&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nuke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;programming&quot;&gt;Programming:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;C#&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Java&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;languages&quot;&gt;Languages:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spanish and English&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/cv.html</link>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Portfolio</title>
            <description>### Swapportunities
&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; controls autoplay loop&gt;&lt;source src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/bSnZyCk.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/4cm4HUH.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cell Biology&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/xc532bY.png&quot; alt=&quot;Molecular Biology&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Ktj5Id1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Protein Biology&quot;&gt;

Short video game for the Oculus Go where you swap competitors instruments for others. Three laboratories were created: Cell biology, molecular biology and protein biology.

I was responsible of: Scouting laboratories, level design, 3D modeling all the environments, texturing, 3D modeling competitor's instruments, 3D modeling weapons, animations, particles and splatter effects, renders for swap sprites, UI elements with Unity.

### Digital Smart Start
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/SBjVFED.png&quot; alt=&quot;Qubit Flex DSS&quot;&gt;&lt;video width=&quot;50%&quot; controls autoplay loop&gt;&lt;source src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/az277l6.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;video width=&quot;50%&quot; controls autoplay loop&gt;&lt;source src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/VY3JlL1.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/7xXS1gE.png&quot; alt=&quot;QuantStudio DSS&quot;&gt;&lt;video width=&quot;50%&quot; controls autoplay loop&gt;&lt;source src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/etgNe5m.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;video width=&quot;50%&quot; controls autoplay loop&gt;&lt;source src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/XzpUPBu.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;

WebGL trainings to set new instruments by Thermo Fisher Scientific divisions. Including workflows for basic essay runs and setting up your new instrument. Five iterations were done: POC, EVOS M5000, QuantStudio 1, Qubit Flex and QuantStudio 3/5. Available &lt;a href=&quot;https://test.apps.thermofisher.com/apps/lms/#/vr-manuals&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.

I was responsible of: Retolopology of CAD files for instruments, modeling environments and accesories, texturing, lighting, animations, highligh system with C#, event system functionality, UI elements with Unity.

### VR Robot
&lt;video width=&quot;100%&quot; controls autoplay loop&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/p7oAcHL.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

POC for managing a Spinnaker Microplate Robot from VR environments with the HTC Vive.

I was responsible of: Retopology of CAD files for instruments, modeling environments and accessories, texturing, animations.
</description>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio.html</link>
          </item>
        
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>